Priya A



Contact

Address:

1680/3, Govindpuri Extension, Kalkaji, New Delhi. 110019

Phone:

+91 9910955337

Email:

priya8724@gmail.com

Languages

English, Hindi and Kannada

Summary

A proficient software developer with than 4.6 years of experience predominantly in Laravel. Well composed team player who could handle multiple projects, work with the multi-discipline team and manage clients from different spectrums.

Skill Highlights

- Expertise in: PHP MVC
 Frameworks-Laravel
- Programming Languages:
 C, C++, Java/J2EE
- Software Packages:
 Visual Studio, MS office,
 my eclipse, Eclipse,
 NetBeans
- Web Server: Apache Server
- Javascript frameworks: node.js,vue.js
- NoSQL: MongoDB

- Platforms: Windows, Linux and UNIX
- Databases: Oracle, MS-Access, SQL Server and MySQL
- Distributed Database:
 HBase
- Distributed Framework: Hadoop
- Web-based technologies: HTML, PHP, AJAX, JQUERY, Javascript, CSS

Experience

Feb 2019 to till date

Laravel PHP Developer: LDS Engineers Private Limited, New Delhi

- Working with designers, Front End and project management staffs to capture requirements for the functional elements of website projects.
- Strong Experience in Design OOA and OOD, Designing web applications from scratch.
- Strong Hands-on experience with: JavaScript, HTML5/CSS.
- Strong Hands-on experience with PHP5 with design patterns.
- Strong Hands-on experience in MVC architecture and knowledge in any of the frameworks Laravel
- Building REST APIs
- Proficient understanding code versioning tools such as Git, bitbucket.
- Strong Hands-on experience with Database like MySQL
- Able to work as an individual contributor/team player and take up complete modules end-to-end with minimal supervision
- Strong hands-on experience with AWS server startup through commands
- Managing front end based application stacks like Node JS / Express JS
- Experience with API integration and development
- Experience with Payment Gateway like stripe.

Major Clients/Projects handled

- https://one.gpex.com.au
 GPEx is South Australia's regional training organisation for education and training of doctors who choose to specialise in General Practice (GP). GPEx delivers the AGPT (Australia General Practice Training) Program which is funded by the Department of Health, Australian Government.
 https://gpex.com.au)
- https://learn.gpex.org.au/
- https://coursecommerce.elightenm
 ent.com/
- https://www.gurulearning.ca/onling-ch/
 e/
- https://www.elightenment.com
- https://airflow.in/

Personal Profile

Date of Birth: 24-11-1987 Marital Status: Married Husband Name: Pavan Kumar Daughter: Kum. Prabudha (4.5

years)

Hobbies:

- Watching Movies
- Travelling
- Learning new skills
- Cooking

Reference:

On request

Experience

March 2014 to Feb 2016

PHP Full Stack Developer: Info CRAFT Solutions Exchange Private Limited, New Delhi

- Working on ERP Project like SAP similar projects
- Working with third-party APIs and libraries.
- Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks.
- Coding with OOPs concepts (MVC pattern).
- Troubleshoot, test and maintain the core product software and databases to ensure strong optimization and functionality
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using ¡Query& other libraries.
- Developed the independent component using OOPs concept
- Maintained and modified existing applications as per requirements.
- Documenting features, technical specifications & infrastructure requirements
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Working with a multi-disciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.
- Worked with Google API, FACEBOOK API, LINKEDIN API.
- Developed TRANSACTION API.
- Implementation of HTML/CSS Bootstrap API(designing)
- Theme integration with PHP code development.
- Worked with Google Maps API.
- worked with Google Line chart API, Morris graph API
- Back end development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Experience with FileZilla/FTP Server, SVN/GIT and Cpanel.

Sept 2013 to March 2014

Junior PHP Developer: T9L Technologies Private Limited, New Delhi Responsibilities and key tasks accomplished:

- Responsible for creating and implementing an array of Web-based products using PHP, MySQL, Ajax, and JavaScript.
- To develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services, and assist front-end developers by ensuring their work integrates with the application

Education

Master of Computer Applications (MCA) from Visvesvaraya Technological University, Karnataka

Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA) from Mangalore University, Karnataka